欢迎回来。
Welcome back.
现在让我们编写我们的第一行代码
Let's now write our very first line of code
并建立我们的第一个
and build our very first
和非常小的网页。
and very small webpage.
所以我们回到 VS Code，
So here we are back in VS Code,
现在让我们结束这一切，
and let's now close all of this up,
然后我们将转到第一个选项卡。
and then we're going here to this first tab.
所以这个资源管理器选项卡。
So this Explorer tab.
所以在 VS Code 中，
So in VS Code,
我们总是需要在某个文件夹中。
we always need to be inside of some folder.
该文件夹称为项目文件夹。
And that folder is called the project folder.
现在，现在我们没有
Now, right now we don't have
任何文件夹都开始了。
any folders started yet.
所以让我们开始吧
And so let's actually start by doing that
我将创建一个文件夹
and I will create a folder
就在我的桌面上。
right here on my desktop.
所以基本上我会做所有的，
So basically I will do all the,
所有的编码都会发生
all the coding will always happen
在我的桌面上，
here on my desktop,
但当然你也可以这样做
but of course you can also do it
在您计算机上的任何其他位置。
in any other place on your computer.
这个其实无所谓
This one doesn't really matter,
对我来说，这更容易
for me, it's just easier
把它放在桌面上。
to have it on the desktop.
我在这里调用这个文件夹
And I'm calling this folder here
01 和测试。
01 and Test.
好的。
Okay.
所以让我们回到这里
So let's go back here
现在点击打开文件夹。
and now click on open folder.
所以去我的桌面，
And so going to my desktop,
我现在将选择此文件夹
I will now select this folder
我刚刚创建的。
that I just created.
所以这个 01 Test 现在是我们的项目文件夹。
And so this 01 Test is now our project folder.
所以你看，
So you see,
我们得到一个新的欢迎屏幕
we get a new welcome screen
在这里我们可以点击新文件
and here we can click on new file
将我们的第一个文件添加到项目中。
to add our very first file to the project.
或者我们也可以这样做
Or we could also do this
将鼠标悬停在此左侧边栏上
by hovering here over this left sidebar
并单击此处的新文件图标。
and clicking here on the new file icon.
所以这是两种不同的方式
So these are two different ways
在项目文件夹中创建新文件。
of creating new files in the project folder.
我实际上更喜欢这里的这个。
And I actually prefer this one here.
所以我们要创建
So we are about to create
我们的第一个网页
our very first webpage
网页基本上只是一个 HTML 文件，
and a webpage is basically just an HTML file,
我们称之为 index.html。
and let's call it index.html.
所以它基本上只是文件
So it's basically just the file
带有 HTML 文件扩展名。
with the HTML file extension.
我们称之为索引
And we are calling it index
因为这是默认名称
because that is the default name
任何网站的第一页。
of the first page of any website.
所以索引基本上总是
So index is basically always
任何网站的入口点。
the entry point to any website.
所以所有的网络项目
And so all web projects
总是需要有一个 index.html。
always need to have an index.html.
好的。所以记住这一点，
All right. So keep that in mind,
始终调用您的第一页 index.html。
always call your very first page index.html.
现在我这次讲座的目标还没有
Now my goal in this lecture is not yet
真正教你HTML。
to really teach you HTML.
现在，
Right now,
我要做的就是创建这个文件
all I want to do is to create this file
并为其添加一点代码
and to add a little bit of code to it
然后在浏览器中查看结果。
and then see the results in the browser.
只是为了让你写作
Just so you get to write
你的第一行代码
your first line of code
并且能够看到结果
and are able to see the results
在真正的网络浏览器中编写该代码。
of writing that code in a real web browser.
再说一次，我并没有真正开始教 HTML
So again, I'm not really starting to teach HTML
刚刚。
just yet.
所以不是写一个完整的页面结构，
And so instead of writing a whole page structure,
正如我们通常需要的那样，
as we usually need to,
我们将使用一个小作弊
we are going to use a small cheat
我们可以在 VS Code 中使用。
that we can use in VS Code.
所以要做到这一点，只需写一个感叹号。
So to do that, just write an exclamation mark.
所以就这样，
So just like this,
然后你可以点击你的标签键盘，
and then you can hit tab on your keyboard,
或者您也可以单击此处。
or you can also just click here.
有了这个，
And with that,
我们得到了这个非常基本的
we get this very basic
和几乎空的 HTML 结构。
and almost empty HTML structure.
所以它有一个头，它有一个身体。
So it has a head and it has a body.
但再一次，
But once again,
我们将了解这一切
we will learn all about that
稍晚一些。
a little bit later.
现在，我感兴趣的都在这里
For now, all I'm interested here
现在是网页的这个标题。
is for now this title of the webpage.
所以让我们在这里更改内容
So let's change the content here
例如，这个标题
of this title to, for example,
“我的第一个网页。”
"My first webpage."
但是当然你也可以写
But of course you can also write
这里有别的东西
something else here
然后让我们进入身体内部。
and then let's go inside of the body.
所以这实际上是部分
So this is actually the part
我们将能够看到
that we will be able to see
在浏览器中。
in the browser.
在这里，只需写下这个小于号。
And here, just write this less than sign.
然后是H1，代表标题一
Then H1, which stands for heading one
然后是大于符号。
and then the greater than symbol.
所以就像这里的这个，
So just like this one here,
然后你会看到 VS Code
and you see that then VS Code
实际上是自动放置的
actually automatically placed
这另一部分在这里。
this other part here.
所以基本上关闭了H1。
So closing the H1 basically.
但又一次，
But again,
现在这并不重要。
that doesn't really matter for now.
让我们在这里写一些文本内容
Let's just write some text content in here
我在写，“你好，世界！”
and I'm writing, "Hello, world!"
有一种标准
which has kind of a standard
当您编写第一行代码时
when you write your very first line of code
在任何编程语言中。
in any programming language.
所以你好世界真的
So hello world is really
悠久的传统。
a long standing tradition.
接下来让我们尝试另一个。
Next let's try another one.
再说一次，这个小于符号。
So again, this less than symbol.
现在让我们试试代表段落的 P。
Now let's try P which stands for paragraph.
然后再一次，
And then again,
VS Code 自动关闭
VS Code automatically closes
我们的段落。
the paragraph for us.
所以让我们说，“我的名字是乔纳斯。”
So let's say, "My name is Jonas."
你当然会用你自己的名字，
And you will of course use your own name,
“这是我的第一次
"And this is my very first
网页。”
webpage."
好的。
Okay.
现在我们可以给它一个保存
Now we can give it a save
通过点击命令或控制 S
by hitting command or control S
或者您也可以转到此处的文件菜单。
or you can go here to the file menu as well.
我们还启用了自动保存功能。
And we also have the auto save active.
所以如果我们只是离开这个选项卡，例如，
So if we just leave this tab, so for example,
点击此处外部，
by clicking outside here,
然后它也会自动保存文件。
then it will also automatically save the file.
所以让我们实际尝试一下。
So let's actually try that.
现在我们开始。
And here we go.
所以现在文件已经保存了，
So now the file has been saved,
也许你也注意到了
and maybe you also noticed
格式已更改
that the formatting has changed
这里一点点，
here a little bit,
发生这种情况是因为
and this happened because
Prettier 扩展的
of the Prettier extension that
我们在上一个视频中安装。
we installed in the last video.
所以请记住 Prettier 扩展
So remember that the Prettier extension
是自动格式化或编码
is to format or code automatically
每当我们保存它。
whenever we save it.
这正是刚刚发生的事情。
And so that is exactly what just happened.
所以让我们在这里添加一些空格
So let's just add some spaces here
现在如果我再次点击命令或控制 S，
and now if I hit command or control S again,
然后你会看到它把它放回去
then you'll see it put it back
在正确的地方。
in the correct place.
好的。
All right.
这就是 Prettier 的力量
And so that's the power of Prettier
它将确保您的代码
and it will ensure that your code
应该总是一样的
should always look the same
正如视频中的这段代码。
as this code in the video.
伟大的。
Great.
所以我们只写了我们的第一行代码，
So we just wrote our very first line of code,
或者实际上，我们的前两行代码。
or actually, our first two lines of code.
所以现在我们有了这个 index.html 文件
And so now we have this index.html file
我们可以在浏览器中打开它。
and we can open it up in a browser.
所以让我们去我们的项目文件夹
So let's go to our project folder
该文件所在的位置。
where this file is located.
就我而言，请记住，那是在桌面上。
And in my case, remember, that's on the desktop.
所以我只能打开它。
So I can just open it.
现在我们有了 index.html 文件
And now here we have that index.html file
我们之前在 VS Code 中创建的。
that we created previously in VS Code.
现在在谷歌浏览器中打开它
And to now open it up in Google Chrome
或在任何其他浏览器中，
or in any other browser,
我们只需要双击文件，
we just need to double click the file,
或者我们也可以，点击它
or we can just also right, click it
然后用谷歌浏览器打开。
and then open with a Google Chrome.
所以让我们这样做。
So let's do that.
在这里，
And here it is,
这是我们的第一个网页
here is our very first webpage
我们刚刚在 VS Code 中手动创建的。
that we just created manually in VS Code.
伟大的。
Great.
如果你问我，那真的很神奇，
And that's really amazing if you ask me,
恭喜你，干得好
so congratulations and well done
在您的第一个网页上。
on your very first web page here.
让我们把它推到一边
Let's just push it to the side here
一点点，然后 VS Code 到另一边。
a little bit and then VS Code to the other side.
所以从现在开始，我们将永远拥有，
So from now on, we will always have,
我们的代码在左边
our code here on the left side
然后在右侧的浏览器
and then on the right side the browser
这样我们就可以看到我们的变化。
so that we can see our changes.
为了给我们更多的空间，
And to give us a bit more space here,
我们可以再次，
we can, again,
单击此处的此选项卡
click on this tab here
然后就会崩溃
and that will then collapse
侧边栏并给我们更多空间
the sidebar and give us more space
对于我们的实际代码。
for our actual code.
所以你在这里看到，
So you see that here,
我们有这个大而粗体的hello world。
we have this hello world in big and bold text.
所以这对应于这个 H1 元素，
And so that corresponds here to this H1 element,
然后在下面我们有这一段，
and then below that we have this paragraph,
在这里翻译
which is translated here
进入这个视觉元素。
into this visual element.
我们也有实际的标题
We also have the actual title
在此选项卡的标题中的页面。
of the page here in the title of this tab.
所以“我的第一个网页”就是我们这里的内容，
So "My first webpage" is what we have here,
这正是我们在这里输入的
and that is exactly what we typed here
进入标题元素。
into the title element.
对？
Right?
再一次，
And so one more time,
我们在这里写的代码
the code that we wrote here
在我们的 HTML 文档中
in our HTML document
现在反映在现实世界中
is now reflected in the real world
在这个真正的网络浏览器中。
in this real web browser.
说到网络浏览器，
And speaking of the web browser,
我正在使用谷歌浏览器进行测试
I'm using Google Chrome to test
我们要写的所有代码
all the codes that we're gonna write
在整个课程中。
throughout this course.
所以我真的建议你
And so I really advise you
也使用谷歌浏览器
to also use Google Chrome
始终测试您正在编写的代码。
to always test the code that you are writing.
所以这将再次，
So that will, again,
确保您有准确的
ensure that you have the exact
与您看到的结果相同
same results as you are seeing
在课程视频中。
in the course videos.
好的。
Okay.
这实际上就足够了
And this is actually enough
对于第一个编码视频。
for this very first coding video.
我希望你真的会得到
And I hope that you will really get
我想向你展示的想法
the ideas that I wanted to show you
在本次讲座中。
in this lecture.
所以基本上从创造开始
So basically starting from creating
一个项目文件夹，
a project folder,
然后在 VS Code 中打开该项目文件夹。
then opening up that project folder in VS Code.
所以这里的这个文件夹是test文件夹，
So this folder here to test folder,
然后在里面，
then inside of that,
创建一个 HTML 文件，
creating an HTML file,
然后添加一些代码文件
then adding some code to that file
最后打开
and finally opening up
真实浏览器中的 HTML 文档，
the HTML document in a real browser,
比如谷歌浏览器，
such as Google Chrome,
然后我们看到这个结果。
where we then see this result.
所以基本上我们代码的翻译
So basically the translation of our code
到视觉效果。
to a visual result.
所以我希望你玩得开心
So I hope that you had some fun doing this,
我会在下一个视频中见到你。
and I see you in the next video.